Geoff Groenendale

Professional Summary

Business Analyst with 5 years' experience in data analysis, systems analysis, and requirements gathering. Expert in collaborating between business and technical teams to translate requirements and limitations. Experience and education with Project Management and Systems Analysis methodologies including Agile, PMI, and Six Sigma. Thorough technical experience in data maintenance, data visualization, and business process automation for faster decision making and improved oversight.

Experience

Business Data Analyst – *Rexel/Platt*

September 2021 – March 2023

Department Scorecard Dashboard -

• Worked with Department leaders to gather important KPI's to track and inform leadership of performance and impact to business using Power BI for the visuals.

Database Team -

- Developed a process to analyze the links between API Routes and Database Resources.
- Implemented Azure DevOps Wiki for database documentation, process documentation, and other team resources

Data Integration for New Acquisition –

- Modeled the data entities and relationships for internal sales application to guide integration of newly acquired business.
- Documented Integration process to guide additional application integrations and for future business acquisitions.

Business Systems Analyst - *The Standard*

May 2020 - April 2021

Short Term Disability Claimant Correspondence System -

- Configured user interface based on stakeholder requirements.
- Lead several meetings to clarify requirements and validate user requirements
- Wrote thorough documentation for future improvements

VBA Script Automation for Data oversight -

• Improved validation processes by collecting data on XML files using VBA scripts

Data Analytics Teaching Assistant – *University of Oregon / 2U*

May 2019 – December 2020

Programming and Technical Skills -

- Detailed best practices like code documentation and control systems like Git, GitHub and GitLab.
- Complex technologies like Machine Learning, large datasets, and working with cloud infrastructures

Data Analytics -

- Programming in Python for data manipulation, cleaning, analysis, and storage.
- Storing data in relational databases such as MySQL, Postgres, and SQLite as well as non-relational databases such as MongoDB.
- Guided Students through the designing data schemas, documenting work, and managing change.

Data Visualization -

- Built web apps using JavaScript, HTML, and CSS for data visualization as well as common libraries D3.js, Leaflet, and Bootstrap.
- Built dashboards using Tableau for fast data visualization turn around.

Geoff Groenendale



Technology Analyst – *TEC Equipment*

May 2019 – December 2019

Diesel Service Department Technology Assessment -

- Learned Service Department processes in functional and technical detail to understand technology gaps and issues
- Built a report to summarize major and minor issues in Service Departments costing the entire organization \$3 million in lost productive time due to outdated wireless systems and design specification

Job Schedule Dashboard Web App -

- Gathered requirements and learned process flow from Service Managers and Advisors
- Designed and developed web-based dashboard system and API for Service Departments.

Business Intelligence Analyst – *Market Contractors*

Mar 2017 - Oct 2017

Construction Project Status Reports -

- Aggregated data from Sage 300, Salesforce, and project spreadsheets to produce information for Project Managers, Account Managers, and Executive Management.
- Determined financial standing and completeness of 150 construction projects over 3 different client programs for decision making.

Website Redesign Project -

- Initiated company website redesign by gathering resources and requirements from stakeholders.
- Created wireframes and basic designs and documented underlying limitations of current system

Assistant Buyer - Crown Enterprises dba Tri-State Outfitters

Jan 2013 – Jun 2014

Weekly Inventory Orders -

- Pulled sales reports and inventory levels on over 50,000 items across two departments and five stores.
- Created Purchase Order records for shipping and accounting validation

Data Maintenance -

- Adjusted inventory levels due to theft and error
- Maintained accurate barcode, item number, and manufacturer numbers

Education

Bachelor of Arts in Business Administration Washington State University – Vancouver, WA – May 2019

Major: Management Information Systems | Minor: Digital Technology and Culture

Associates in General Studies Columbia Basin College – Pasco, WA – May 2011

Major: Mechanical Engineering Prep

Skills and Competencies

Project Management – Experience with Azure DevOps, Jira, Confluence, Trello, GitHub, Microsoft Project, **Analysis** – Tableau, Power BI, Microsoft Visio, Microsoft Excel

Programming – Experienced with Python, C#, JavaScript, VBA, PHP. Linux and Windows Administration.

Database Administration and Management – Experienced with MongoDB, Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, Neo4j, PostgreSQL, and SQLite. Familiar with ElasticSearch.